美国家庭影院 出品
联合制作: 梦工厂 与 PLAYTON公司
领衔主演:科克・阿塞沃多 埃昂・贝利 迈克尔・库德利兹
戴尔・戴伊 里克・格梅兹 斯科特・格里米斯
弗兰克・约翰・休伊斯 达米安・路易斯 朗・利文斯通
詹姆斯・马迪奥 尼尔・麦克唐纳 雷内・L・莫雷诺
道格拉斯・斯佩恩 理察・斯贝特 唐尼・沃尔伯格
角色的分派: 利伯曼/巴顿
视觉效果总监:安格斯・ 比克尔顿
特殊效果监督员: 乔斯・威廉姆斯
服装设计师: 安娜・谢帕德
编辑:约翰・理查兹
音乐:迈克尔・凯曼
制作设计 : 安东尼・布拉特
摄影指导:雷米・阿德法拉欣
监督指导: 艾力克・简得森
制作人: 玛丽・理查兹
监督制片人: 埃里克・ 柏克
联合执行制片人: 史蒂芬・安布洛斯 加里・高依兹曼 托尼・ 托
执行制片人:汤姆・汉克斯 斯蒂文・斯皮尔伯格
兄弟连作者: 史蒂芬・安布洛斯
编剧:埃里克・延德里森
导演:汤姆・汉克斯
兄 弟 连
如果你是个领导者 凡事就得带头
If you're a leader, you lead the way.
不只是轻松的事
Not just on the easy ones.
还包括艰难的任务
You take the tough ones, too.
好的领导者
A good leader has to understand...
必须了解他的属下 必须了解他们的欲求
...the people that are under him, understand their needs...
以及他们的想法
...their desires or how they think a little bit.
他似乎一路走来 总是做出正确的抉择
It seemed like he always made the right decisions along the way.
他是个真正的军人
He was a real soldier.
像其他的一些军官
Like, some of the officers...
我想我不会听从他们的指挥
...I don't think I'd follow them into water.
但是 他是最棒的
But he was one of the best.
他不管情况如何马上投入
He went right in there and he didn't know.
他从没想过要落人之后
He never thought of not being first...
或是找人替代
...or sending somebody in his place.
我不知道他怎么存活下来
I don't know how he survived.
但他做到了
But he did.
第五集
十 字 路 口
( 1944年10月17日 荷兰 史空德洛特 )
路?
Lew?
醒醒! 他们要我们回团部
Wake up. They want us back at regiment.
快点 尼克 起床了! 我们走!
Come on, Nix, get up. Let's go.
快点 有事发生了 史崔尔的命令
Come on, something's up. Strayer's orders.
你先走 我马上下来
Okay, I'll be right down.
- 快点 还有十分钟 - 别烦我~
- Let's go, come on, you got 10 minutes. - Go away.
起来 大家伙! 咱们走!
Come on, big guy, let's go.
- 别烦我~ - 好吧
- Leave me alone. - Okay.
- 走啦! - 可恶!
- Come on. - Goddamn it.
老天 这是我自己的尿
That's my own piss, for Christ's sake.
王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
我们是唯一在德国的莱茵河岸遭遇到德军的盟军部队
We're the only unit in the group that's got the Germans on the German side of the Rhine.
我不是说这很容易 但若老早攻下安特卫普
If we'd have taken Antwerp and I'm not saying that would be easy...
我们早就渡过河 带着充足的补给打得德军乱窜
...we'd be over the river, well supplied, and have the Krauts on their heels.
我只要能让艾森豪威尔听电话就好 你在听我说吗?
Now, if I can just get lke on the phone... Are you listening to me?
一字不漏
Hangin' on every word.
( 团指挥部 )
穆斯 你也来了?
Hey, Moose, you too?
对 不管怎样 辛克的脸好臭
Yeah, whatever's going on, Sink is not happy.
尼克森 海立格 见过英军第一空降师的都比中校
Nixon, Heyliger. Meet Col. Dobie, British 1st Airborne.
尼克森上尉是第二营指挥官 这是穆斯海立格中尉
Capt. Nixon is our 2nd Battalion S-2. That's First Lt. Moose Heyliger.
英军在市场花园作战损失了8000名弟兄
It appears the British lost 8,000 men when Market Garden fell on its ass...
所以都比中校来此协调救援行动
...which is why Col. Dobie has been tasked with coordinating a rescue operation...
救出安恒沦陷时被困的红魔鬼部队
...for the Red Devils trapped when Arnhem fell.
荷兰抵抗组织在河北岸15里一座沦陷城镇外收容了我们的140位弟兄
Dutch resistance are harboring 140 of my chaps here just outside a Jerry-held town 15 miles north of the river.
我们今晚将设法抵达河岸在此处森林里集合
They'll go to the riverbank and gather in the woods tonight.
从Ｅ连选出一个小队 尽快带他们过莱茵河
Pick a team and get them back across the Rhine as fast as possible.
140位弟兄?
140 men?
加拿大工兵提供了六艘船
Canadian engineers have supplied six boats.
集结点很独立 且能登陆
The rendezvous point is isolated and landable.
我昨晚自己游过一遍 凌晨3时
I swam it myself last night. At approximately 0030 hours...
他们会以红色火把做出"V"字的胜利信号
...they will signal the "V" for victory with a handheld red torch.
美国说法是红色手电筒
That would be a handheld red flashlight.
我们叫这次行动"飞马作战"
We'll call this Operation Pegasus.
鲍伯 你们第二营负责任务
Bob, your 2nd Battalion is on the spot. Get it Done.
你尽力协助都比中校
Capt. Nixon, assist Col. Dobie in every way possible.
如果有什么需要尽管找我
If you need anything at all, you come to me.
- 我已经很满意了 - 温特斯上尉
- I can hardly ask for more. - Capt. Winters.
我还没看到你在市场花园任务报告上的签名
You haven't endorsed the Market Garden after-action report...
也没有你最新的营编制表 这是怎么回事?
...or the updated Battalion TO and E. Why is that?
我会在下午1点前交到指挥所
I'll have them at CP at 1300, sir.
我还要一份英军43师留下来的物资清单
I want an inventory on any material the British 43rd left behind:
包括口粮 医疗补给 运输工具
Rations, medical supplies, transport.
- 一份清单 是 长官 - 迪克
- An inventory. Yes, sir. - Dick.
我一直在等着写10月5日作战的褒扬令
I'm still waiting to write citations on that 5 October operation.
- 我需要你的报告 - 报告 是 长官
- I need your report. - The report. Yes, sir.
- 你要加把劲了 迪克 - 是的
- Light a fire under it, Dick. - Sir.
我们昨天就要这个
Now, goddamn it, we asked for this yesterday...
结果今天才给我 整整迟一天
...and here it is today, a day late and a dollar short.
情报单位的敌军部署及地图 我们该参考一下
Enemy disposition and maps in the S-2. We should have a look at that.
你说那儿约有一百人?
You say there's about 100 of 'em?
( Ｅ连在1944年10月5日之战 )
就是这样 各位
This is it, boys.
他们得先渡河 穿过旷野和堤道
Get across the river, across the field and over the dike.
可得越过一大片地区 你要我们去哪儿?
That's a lot of territory to cover. Where you want us to go?
你吗 赫胥? 你上阁楼去
You, Hashey, you get the penthouse.
谢谢你 我们上楼去
Thank you. We're up top.
- 情况有多糟? - 你会知道的
- How bad does it get? - You'll find out.
- 要涵盖的区域还真广 - 就靠几个美国大兵 是吧?
- That's a lot of territory to cover. - A couple of regular GI Joe's?
没错! 走吧!
You said it. Come on.
新进弟兄在带补充兵熟悉环境
New guys giving the replacements the what-for, and why-is.
我敢说他们有人还未成年呢
I swear one of them's never shaved.
- 对 是群孩子 - 这可是只了不起的狗 泰柏
- Yeah, kids. - This is a hell of a dog, Tab.
谢谢你 这个给你
Thank you, there you go.
- 你叫它什么 泰柏? - 扳机
- What'd you call it, Tab? - Trigger.
很好 我喜欢 扳机
That's good. I like that. Trigger.
有什么动静吗?
Got anything on this?
- 没有 都很安静! - 我们被渗透了!
- No, it's all quiet. - We've got penetration!
- 艾利受伤了 我们需要医生 - 把他抬到桌子上
- Alley's hurt, get the doc. - Get him on the table.
艾利 是艾利
Yeah, it's Alley.
- 好了 这个我来拿 - 艾利 你会没事的
- All right, I got this. - Alley, you're gonna be okay.
- 波勒 快去找罗医生来 - 我在哪里?
- Boyle, get Doc Roe. - Where am I?
- 发生了什么事? - 在哪?
- Something happened - What happened? - Where was it?
十字路口 马路跟堤道交汇处
Crossroads, where the road crosses the dike.
要不是你的大嗓门 他们也不会发现
They knew we was there because of your loud mouth.
乔 别吵了
Joe, back off.
莱斯尼斯基 派传令找威尔旭中尉
Lesniewski, send a runner for Lt. Welsh.
- 中尉 派个班给我 - 第一班 起立!
- Assemble me a squad. - Yes, sir. 1st Squad, on your feet!
- 只带武器弹药! - 让我过
- Weapons and ammo only! - Give me room.
快 我们走
Let's move! Let's go!
波勒 把他的鞋脱掉 把腿抬高
Boyle, get the boots off, elevate the leg.
李高特! 用硫磺
Liebgott, use the sulfur.
好 赶紧把它搞定 我们必须快点
Let's get this done quickly, we got to move.
不用洒太多
Not too much.
艾利 没事了
Alley.
- 是MG42机枪吗? - 对!
- MG-42? - Yeah.
他们在向谁射击?
What the hell are they shootin' at?
- 马路那头有什么? - 团部指挥所
- What's down that road? - Regimental headquarters.
但那是在三里之外 他们为何要自暴位置?
But that's three miles away. Why are they giving away their position?
因为他们没有你我聪明?
They ain't as smart as me and you?
我还是得去看一下 留在这等我信号
I'll check it out anyway. Hold here, wait for my signal.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
在这里等 我在等信号
Holding here, I'm waitin' for a signal.
这是我们撤退的位置
This is our fallback position, here.
迫击炮部署在这里 第一班 跟我来
Mortars, deploy here. 1st Squad, on me.
走
Go.
右边第二个
Second on the right.
右边第一个
First on the right.
右边第三个 把机枪歼灭
Third on the right. Nail the machine gun.
左边第二个 左边第一个
Second on the left, first on the left.
等我的信号
Wait for my signal.
准备开火
Prepare to fire.
两发点放 连放不修正
Two rounds, AG, quick.
- 撤退! - 发射!
- Fall back! - Fire.
发射
Fire.
德军在堤道上 12点钟方向
Higgins! Handful of Krauts, based on the dike, 12:00!
- 上面还有多少德军? - 我不知道
- How many Krauts are left up there? - I don't know.
我们一次就干掉七个
But we got seven in one blow.
快去找波勒和派康提来!
Bring on Boyle and Perconte, go!
快点 撤退!
Come on, fall back.
压制射击
Suppressing fire.
压制射击!
Suppressing fire!
哈许 贾西亚 跟我来
Hashey, Garcia, follow me.
哈利 叫皮卡克把第一排剩下的弟兄带过来
Harry, tell Peacock to bring up the balance of 1st Platoon on the double!
还有再带一个机枪班来 完毕
And another machine-gun squad, over.
杜克曼!
Dukeman!
去把右侧的机枪干掉 去!
Go get that machine gun on the right flank, go!
克里斯登生!
Christenson!
杜克曼挂了
Fuck, Dukeman's down.
长官 第一排剩余兄弟到了
Sir, the balance of 1st Platoon are here.
戈登跟摩尔到了 另一挺30机枪
Gordon and More brought another 30 cal.
长官
Sir.
他们在坚固的堤岸后方
They're behind a solid roadway embankment.
我们则在壕沟 他们想通的话...
We're in a ditch. They can outflank us along the dike...
就可沿着堤道两侧夹击消灭我们
...and catch us out here as soon as they figure that out.
我们要面对多少德军?
So, how many Krauts are we talking about?
有艘运兵船通过这里
There's a ferry crossing here...
就我所知可能有一整营
...so, it could be a whole battalion, as far as I know.
好 那你的指示呢?
Okay, what are your orders?
我们别无选择
We got no choice.
计划是这样的 泰柏特 你带十个人沿堤道走
Here it is. Talbert, you'll take ten men along the dike.
皮卡克 你带十个人沿左侧走
Peacock, you'll take ten men along the left flank.
我带十个攻中路 大家跟紧我
I'll take ten up the middle, so follow me.
有问题吗? 去吧!
Questions? Go!
进来
Enter.
不知道为何我还改不过来
I don't know why I'm still doing this.
是说喝酒吧?
What, drinking?
不是 是把酒藏在你的置物柜
No, hiding it in your footlocker.
我都已经是上尉了耶
I'm a captain, for Christ's sake.
那你何不...
Why don't you...
干脆改掉?
Why don't you just give it up?
戒酒?
Drinking?
不 在我柜子藏酒的习惯
No, hiding it in my footlocker.
你已经是上尉了耶
You're a captain, for Pete's sake.
也许你是对的 也许这是戒酒的最佳地点
Maybe you're right and this is the perfect place to stop drinking.
就在盟军前锋的端点
Right here on the business end of the Allied advance.
敬你
Cheers.
迪克 那不是文学创作 简洁就好
Dick, you know, that's not literature. You just keep it simple.
试着用第一人称复数
Try writing it in the first person plural, you know.
- 就是多用"我们" - 谢谢提示
- Say "we" a lot. - Thanks for the tip.
上刺刀
Fix bayonets.
等红色烟雾信号
Go on the red smoke.
等一下 等信号
No, wait! Wait for the signal.
老天
Jesus.
弟兄们 上!
Move on,brothers
机枪上来
机枪架在这里
弟兄们 上!
Come on, boys!
四
Four.
五
Five.
我的老天!
Holy shit!
- 又来了一整连! - 没错!
- It's a whole other company! - No shit!
开火 开火 开火!
Fire, fire, fire.
Ｅ连Ｂ呼叫Ｅ连Ｍ 请求对黄一区火力支援
Easy Beaver to Easy Minor. Reinforce Easy at phase one yellow.
加一百码 三群密集射击
Plus one, strike three. Fire concentration Charlie.
再减两百码 向左一百码
Dropped 200, left 100.
重复 加一百码 三群密集射击
Repeat, plus one, strike three.
集中火力 再减两百码 向左一百码
Fire concentration Charlie. Dropped 200, left 100.
德军在空旷地 有效攻击 完毕
Krauts in the open, fire for effect, over.
不许动(德语)
Heraus, Hande hoch. Schnell, schnell!
- 他说什么? - 他跟我说他们是波兰人
- What's he saying? - He's telling me that they're Polish.
波兰人? 鬼才相信! 党卫军里是没有波兰人
Don't you believe it. There ain't no Poles in the SS!
快走!
Move!
天啊
Jesus Christ
可恶!
Shit!
鲁兹! 给炮指挥所攻击报告 波勒!
Luz, send Lightning a contact report. Boyle!
到上头可以看见弹着点的地方
Get up where you can spot the fall of those rounds, go!
敌炮射击!
Incoming rogues!
Ｅ连 找掩体
Easy Company, take cover!
- 波勒中弹了! - 他们打中我了
- Boyle's hit! - Jesus Christ, they got me.
找掩体 这是德军炮火
Take cover, it's German artillery.
去救波勒! 他中弹了 快点 帮我
Get Boyle, he's down, come on, help me.
老天 上尉! 他们是党卫军
Jesus, Captain, they're SS.
乔?
Joe?
- 乔...别闹了! - 可恶 干嘛?
- Joe, knock it off. - Damn it, what?
- 你在流血 - 没事 上尉
- You're bleeding. - It's nothing, Captain.
你带这些俘虏回营指挥所
Take these prisoners back to Battalion CP.
- 给自己清洗包扎 - 是
- Get yourself cleaned up. - Yes, sir.
来吧 德国鬼子
Come on, Kraut boys.
- 乔? - 什么事
- Joe? - Yeah.
- 弹药缴出来 - 什么?
- Drop your ammo. - What?
- 把枪给我 - 开玩笑? 你要干什么?
- Drop your ammo. - You kidding? What are you doing?
- 把你的枪给我 - 上尉
- Give me your weapon. - Captain.
你只有一发...子弹! 强尼 我们有几个战俘?
You have one round. Johnny, how many prisoners do we have?
现在有11个 长官
We got eleven right now, sir. Okay.
你若射杀一个战俘 其他人会攻击你
You drop a prisoner, the rest'll jump you.
我要所有战俘活着押回营部
I want all prisoners back at Battalion CP alive.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
"他们打中我了" 你相信吗?
"They got me." You believe that?
你相信我竟然这么说吗?
You believe I said that?
- 你能撑回营部吗? - 可以
- Can you make it back to CP? - Yeah.
那就好 我们别处再碰头
All right, I will see you someplace else.
把这些带回营部
Take these to Battalion.
- 把他们分开 - 是
- Split 'em up. - Yes, sir.
抬起来! 很好
Up. All right.
喝口水
Here you are.
我打得他们乱窜
We had 'em on the run.
说说看
How's that?
我们炮击时德军刚好蜂拥回渡船口
The Germans were flooding back towards the ferry crossing when we hit 'em with artillery.
就象是在打火鸡
It was like a turkey shoot.
然后他们用88毫米炮反击 集中在这十字路口
Then they hit us with their 88s, zeroed in on this crossroad.
我们算是走运了
Now we were lucky, though.
只有22个人受伤
Only 22 wounded.
运气好?
Lucky?
- 温特斯上尉呢? - 就在下面 长官
- Capt. Winters? - He's right down there, sir.
好 继续工作
All right, carry on.
好了 德国佬 手举起来
All right, Krauts, Hande hoch.
22人受伤? 你还好吗?
22 wounded? You okay?
- 还好 有一人阵亡 - 谁?
- Yeah, one killed. - Who?
杜克曼
Dukeman.
你们碰到的可是整整两连的党卫军
You're looking at two full companies of SS out there.
歼灭大约50人 可能100人受伤
About 50 dead, probably another 100 wounded.
营部牢里有7个 再加上上头还有一整串
Seven back in the regimental cage plus a whole string of 'em up there.
对杜克曼而言不算太坏
That's not bad for Dukeman.
你有喝的吗?
You got a drink?
水?
Of water?
对 这是水
Yeah, it's water.
谢了
Thanks.
还好吗?
Okay?
德军第363炮兵团在今早炮击欧福斯登
363rd Volksgrenadier hit Opheusden early this morning...
大约同时党卫军对我的指挥所发动攻击
...about the same time your SS made a run for my CP down the road.
第三营被他们重创
3rd Battalion got the hell beat out of 'em.
- 哈利贺顿阵亡了 - 贺顿少校死了?
- Holly Horton was killed. - Maj. Horton's dead?
他们猛烈攻击第二营指挥部
They hit 2nd Battalion CP in force.
他当时在进行防御工作
He was organizing the defense.
尼克森上尉 失陪一下
Capt. Nixon, excuse us for just a minute.
你对管理营部有何想法?
How'd you feel about handling the battalion?
长官?
Sir?
我要升你做第二营主任参谋
I'm moving you up to executive officer of 2nd Battalion.
史崔尔中校... 他需要帮手
Col. Strayer is... He could use some help.
- 长官 我在战场上能带兵 - 没错 迪克
- I know I could handle them in the field, sir. - That's right, Dick.
你是个战术家、好领袖! 不用担心行政的事
You're a solid tactician and a good leader. Don't worry about administration.
你认为谁会来带领Ｅ连 长官?
Who do you think'll be taking over Easy, sir?
穆斯海立格将带领Ｅ连
Moose Heyliger can command Easy Company.
海力格中尉也会是我的选择
Lt. Heyliger would be my choice, sir.
很好
Good.
去收拾你的东西 到营指挥所去报到
You pack your gear and come to Battalion CP.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
要来杯咖啡吗 长官?
Would you like some coffee, sir?
- 好的 谢谢你 医生 - 不客气!
- Yeah, thanks, doc. - All right.
迪克!
Dick!
小说完成了吗? 好多家庭作业喔
Finish your novel yet? That's a lot of homework.
我以为参谋是个有趣的工作
And I thought executive officer was a fun job.
- 你是谁? - 奇林斯基 长官
- Who are you? - Zielinski, sir.
- 他是谁? - 奇林斯基是我的勤务兵
- Who is he? - Zielinski, my orderly.
当官的可真有特权
Rank does have its privileges.
勤务兵? 我猜你能做像倒咖啡之类的事?
Orderly? I suppose you do stuff like get coffee.
- 我可以 长官! - 黑咖啡 不加糖
- Can do, sir. - Black, no sugar.
还要培根三明治 你要什么吗?
And a bacon sandwich. You want something?
培根三明治
Bacon sandwich.
把这拿给辛克上校 帮我谢谢他
You can give that to Col. Sink with my compliments.
搞了半天才写两页?
All that for two pages.
我想要等它完成 还有得等了
Guess that means that's gonna take a while.
是的 没错 你需要工作吗?
Yeah, it is. You want a job?
我想有人巴不得赶快回去指挥Ｅ连呢 穆斯
There. I think somebody wishes you were back in charge of Easy Company, Moose.
- 你俩是来幸灾乐祸的吗? - 不 只是来消遣你一下
- Are you two just here to gloat? - No, just rub it in a little bit.
穆斯马上要以连长的身份出第一个任务
Moose is gonna lead his first mission as CO.
"飞马"作战即将展开 我想该跟你说明计划
Operation Pegasus is set to go off. I wanted to give you the heads up.
"飞马" 很好
Pegasus, yeah.
很好 太好了
Yeah, great.
- 大家都清楚任务? - 我们整天都带着小艇演习
- Everybody know their job? - We've drilled with the boats all day.
威尔旭中尉和加拿大工兵都来了
Lt. Welsh is coming along, and the Canadian engineers.
都比中校蛮有一套的
Col. Dobie knows his stuff.
你们要渡河几次?
Know how many times you'll cross the river?
如果真躲着140个英军 3次
If there really are 140 Brits in hiding over there, 3 trips.
速度是关键 何时跃出?
Speed is the key. What time's jump-off?
我们会在凌晨1点到达莱茵河对岸
We'll be at the far side of the Rhine at 0100.
速度是关键! 保持前进 引导部队
Speed is the key. Keep moving and lead the way.
迪克
Dick.
Ｅ连会被好好照顾的
Easy's in good hands.
对
Yeah.
- 那么 好好干! - 你也一样
- Yeah, right. Well, hang tough. - I could say the same to you.
- 祝你好运 穆斯! - 上尉
- Good luck, Moose. - Captain.
- 尼克? - 嗯!
- Nix? - Yeah.
- 你确定这次的情报没问题吧? - 我想没有
- Are we sure on the intelligence of this? - I think it's pretty good.
Ｅ连会不会朝向躲着的德军连队前进?
Is Easy walking into another company of Germans no one can see?
我们何不等穆斯回来时再问他?
Why don't we ask Moose when he gets back?
是的
Right, yeah.
如果他们真的遇上麻烦 你会告诉我吧?
If they do run into any trouble, you'll let me know?
当然
Yeah.
若你看到培根三明治也要告诉我 好吗?
You run into any bacon sandwich, do the same, all right?
好
Yeah.
- 防线安全了 长官! - 返回你的位置 二等兵
- Line secure, sir. - Fall back into position, Private.
我在左翼有一挺30机枪
I got the 30 cal on the left flank.
再把它向左延伸十码
Extend it out to the left, 10 yards.
中校 他们在哪儿?
So, Colonel, where are they?
莱瑟斯特
Leicester. Square.
过来
Come on in.
- 欢迎回来 长官 - 回来真好
- Welcome back, sir. - Good to be back.
我是海立格 101空降师506团
Heyliger, 506 of the 101st Airborne.
从来没想到看到美国佬会这么高兴
Never thought I'd be so glad to see a bloody Yank.
- 交给你了 中校! - 我马上就回来
- Your show, Colonel. - I'll be back shortly.
走吧
Go.
- 螺栓都拴紧了 长官 - 大牛
- Boats are all secure, sir. - Bull.
跟大家说英国人上路了
The Brits are on the way, pass the word.
长官 您这儿漏签了字
Sir, you missed a signature here.
- 穆斯海立格? - 是我 长官
- Moose Heyliger? - That's me, sir.
上帝保佑你
God bless you, my man.
- 我们准备出发了 长官! - 其他人呢?
- We're ready to go, sir. - Where's the rest of you?
好的
Right.
- 我们都到了 - 走吧!
- And here we all are. - Let's go.
杀 穆罕默德!
Wahai, Mohammed! Wahai, Mohammed!
穆斯海立格和美国101空降师
Moose Heyliger and the American 101st...
帮了红魔鬼英军第一空降师一个大忙! 让我们得以回来
...have done the Red Devils a great service, making it possible for us to return...
与敌人择日再战
...and fight the enemy on another day.
敬Ｅ连 还有胜利和葛拉锡!
To Easy Company, victory and Currahee.
团结一致!
Currahee!
我当Ｅ连指挥官不过四个月
I was only Easy's CO for four months, Moose.
( 1944年10月31日 )
Before that it was Meehan's company, and before that Sobel's.
( 荷兰 德里尔 ) 前任连长是米汉 再之前是苏贝尔
对 但你是他们唯一认识的战斗指挥官
But you're the only combat commander they've ever known.
而我是从别的连调来的
And I'm from another company.
你知道他们打哪儿来的 你知道他们经历过什么事
You know where they came from, you know what they've been through.
只要坚持下去
Just hang tough.
训练你的新排长 信赖你的班长
Train your new platoon leaders, and trust your noncoms.
站住!
Halt!
- 我是穆斯... - 不要开枪!
- It's Moose. - Hold your fire!
好的 兄弟
Okay, buddy.
我的天
Oh, my god.
快去找威尔旭中尉来
Send for Lt. Welsh.
你要保持清醒 穆斯!
Stay awake on me, Moose.
看着我立刻去找威尔旭中尉!
Here, look in my eyes. Send for Lt. Welsh, now!
没事的
Okay.
我很抱歉 长官 真抱歉 我不知道
I'm sorry, sir. I'm so sorry. I didn't know.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
- 你是从哪里来的? - 怀俄明州 长官
- Where are you from, trooper? - Wyoming, sir.
你离家好远 阿兵哥
You're a long way from home, Private.
担架! 我来抬!
Stretcher! I got him, Harry.
- 你给他打了吗啡? - 嗯!
- Give him morphine? - Yeah.
- 打了多少? - 不记得了 两三剂
- How much? - I don't know, two, three Syrettes maybe.
- 三剂? - 嗯!
- Three Syrettes maybe? - Yeah.
- 老天 你想害死他吗? - 好像是两针
- Were you trying to kill him? - I think it was two.
重要的是我必须知道他已经被注射了多少剂量
It's important to let me know how much medication he's had.
我在他的夹克没找到注射器
I do not see one Syrette on the man's jacket.
- 我很抱歉 医生 - 还好他身材壮硕 或许还有机会
- Sorry, doc. - Sure is a good thing he's a big man. Maybe he'll stand a chance.
他刚才痛苦不堪 医生 我们不知道该怎么办
We didn't know what to do for his pain.
你们都是军官 成年人 你们应该知道
Yeah, but you are officers, you are grownups, you ought to know.
好了 我们走 快点 走了!
All right, let's go, come on, move it!
∮妈妈 妈妈 你知道吗∮ ( 1944年12月10日 法国 莫米昂李葛兰 )
Mama, mama, can't you see
∮空降部队都对我干了些什么∮
What the airborne's done to me?
- 再一遍 - 向后转
- Once more. - About face.
齐步走
Forward march.
Ｅ连还是只有65%的战力
Easy still has only 65 percent strength...
大部分还是补充兵 包括他们的新连长
...and most of those are replacements, including their new CO.
- 戴克中尉现在如何? - 才到荷兰三个礼拜
- How's Lt. Dike doing? - Three weeks in Holland...
阿兵哥已经叫他散兵坑诺曼
...the guys are already calling him Foxhole Norman.
他们说最早有可能在三月中进行的作战
They're talking about a mid-march action at the earliest.
所以...我们训练新兵三个月 跳伞到柏林 把战争结束
So, we train the guys for three months, we jump into Berlin, we end the war.
唯一将Ｅ连维系在一起的是那些资深的士官们
The only thing holding together Easy Company is the NCOs, Toccoa men.
长官 有位葛奈瑞的士官要见您
Sir, there's a Sgt. Guarnere here to see you.
看看火车带来些什么人
Look what the train brought in.
- 敢死队的! - 上尉 你好!
- The daredevil. - Hiya, Captain.
欢迎回来 比尔
Welcome back, Bill.
老天 是真的 我从来没想过你会坐办公桌
It's true. I never thought I'd see you behind a desk.
对 有天他还会更上层楼
Yeah, and someday he'll sit behind it.
我刚才没有请假 离开营地 从医院来这
I just went awol from the hospital to get back here, sir.
长官 希望不会对你造成麻烦
I hope it won't cause you a problem.
- 就算会 你在乎吗? - 一点也不 长官
- Would you care if it did? - Not a bit, sir.
我带来封穆斯 海立格中尉的信
Got a letter for you here from Moose, Lt. Heyliger, sir.
他在复原中 但得花上段时间
He's recovering, but it's gonna be a long haul.
谢谢你 比尔
Thanks, Bill.
听说要举办足球赛 有从502团来的大块头 是吗?
I hear there's gonna be a football game. Those chumps from the 5-0-deuce, right?
- 没错! 是在圣诞节 - 真棒 空降部队锻炼人
- Yeah, Christmas day. - Great, sky train boys.
我等不及了
Can't wait.
真棒
Great.
我...
I
- 要去找些麻烦了 - 你去吧
- I'll just go find some trouble. - You do that.
- 比尔! - 长官?
- Bill. - Sir?
别再兜风了 好吗?
No more joyriding, right?
有人听过一间叫做..."露露"的酒馆吗?
Anybody ever heard of a little joint called Lulu's?
你难倒我了
You got me.
我四处问问好了
I'll just ask around.
我想现在是时候了
I guess now's as good a time as any.
那是什么? 一张纸? 我不想再看到任何纸
What's that? I don't wanna see another piece of paper.
泰勒将军奉命飞回华盛顿
Gen. Taylor has flown back to Washington.
留下麦考利夫将军指挥
He's left Gen. McAuliffe in charge of the division.
辛克上校去里姆斯见玛琳黛德丽
Col. Sink is in Rheims to see Marlene Dietrich.
- 玛琳黛德丽在里姆斯? - 在劳军联合组织
- Marlene Dietrich is in Rheims? - At the USO.
我要走了 我要去里姆斯
I'm going to Rheims.
史崔尔参加都比中校的婚礼 至少还要在伦敦一礼拜
Strayer is in London for at least a week for Lt. Col. Dobie's wedding.
我则回去爱德布恩找一位年轻的姑娘
I am heading back to Aldbourne to look up a certain young lady.
- 你想告诉我什么? - 我的朋友 你要去巴黎
- What are you telling me? - You, my friend, are headed to Paris.
灯光之都 那是48小时外出假条
City of light. That's a 48-hour pass.
我们决定你需要一点文明的洗礼
It's been decided that you need a little dose of civilization.
旅途愉快(法语)
Bon voyage.
我附议
I second that.
伞兵也一样的强悍
The airborne is as tough as they come.
新兵训练
Basic training.
你知道我在新兵训练做了什么?
You know what I did in basic training?
我得在新兵训练时吃老鼠
I had to eat rats in basic training.
那是我第一次
That's the first time...
先生? (法语)
Monsieur?
这是终点站了(法语)
Monsieur, c'est le terminus. Le train s'arrete ici, on doit tous descendre.
每回我看着你 我看到八个或九个你
Every time I look at you, I see eight or nine of you.
- 当我只看到一个就没事了 - 看着我 我是约翰韦恩
- I'll be all right when I can only see one. - Look at me, I'm John Wayne.
戏服部门帮我弄到这些漂亮的海军制服
The costume department set me up with these great navy whites.
鲁兹 闭嘴
Luz, shut up.
你觉得如何?
What do you think?
- 我在看电影 - 我这部戏看过13遍了
- I'm trying to watch this. - I've seen this movie 13 times, okay?
- 我还没 所以闭嘴! - 好吧 你看
- I haven't, so, shut up. - Watch the movie. It's fine.
- 史基普! - 拜托!
- Skip. - Come on.
你去哪里? 我到处找你
Where've you been? I've been lookin' all over for you.
唐 我本来在老家
Don, I was at home in Tannawanda.
可是被希特勒一搞 我现在在这儿了
But then Hitler started this whole thing, so, now I'm here.
- 你骰子赌得如何? - 还不错
- How'd you make out in craps? - Not so bad.
- 向你借的60块钱 - 你要还我钱?
- Here's the $60 I borrowed. - You're paying me back?
- 还有 要谢谢你! - 令人惊讶!
- And, to say thank you... - Surprising.
- 小费! - 老天!
- ...a tip. - Jesus!
闭嘴!
Shut up! Shut up!
我本来最多赢了六千 可是我现在只剩三千六
I was up $6,000, but I only have $3,600 left.
你要怎么用这些钱?
What will you do with it?
尽快在巴黎花光
Blow most of it in Paris as soon as possible.
分一点红给我
Gimme a tip.
我不认为那里的气候适合你
I don't think that climate in there agrees with you.
事实上 我一直担心你的健康
As a matter of fact I've been worried about your health altogether.
- 巴克! - 你看来不太舒服
- Hey, Buck. - You don't look well.
你觉得如何? 伤口愈合了吗? 四个都好了吗?
How are you feeling? Your wounds heal, all four of them?
你以前看过这电影吗?
You seen this before?
巴克!
Buck.
- 嗨~ - 好看吗?
- Hi. - Is it any good?
很好
Yeah.
- 真是太棒了 - 我一个月前就警告你要小心这姑娘
- It's a real corker. - I warned you about this girl a month ago.
没有人帮你点火吗?
Won't anybody give you a light?
李普 我最喜欢的一段
Lip, favorite part.
你把我想说的都说完了
- "Got a penny? - Got a penny?"
- 有一便士吗? - 有一便士吗?
- "Got a penny?" - Got a penny?
- 怎样? - 有的 这是英国一便士
- What? - It's an English penny...
开灯!
Lights!
- 拜托~ - 安静!
- Come on. - Quiet!
你在干嘛 你不可以对我们这样
You can't do that to the Duke.
我叫你们安静
I said, quiet!
德军党卫军第一装甲师及党卫军第六师装甲师
Elements of the 1st and the 6th SS Panzer Division...
已经突破阿登森林
...have broken through in the Ardennes forest.
他们现在已经击溃第28步兵师及第4师
They've overrun the 28th Infantry and elements of the 4th.
所有军官立刻向所属指挥部报到 休假取消!
All officers report to respective HQs. All passes are cancelled.
征召兵向营区所属排长报到
Enlisted men report to barracks and your platoon leaders.
可恶 真是多事的一天
Damn, what a day.
有火吗?
Got a light?
- 长官? - 皮卡克中尉?
- Sir? - Lt. Peacock?
- 请问有看到史崔尔中校吗? - 你们连长到哪儿去了?
- Sir, have you seen Col. Strayer? - Where's the company commander?
戴克中尉吗? 我整天都在找他
Lt. Dike, I've been looking for him all day.
陆军第四师的麻烦怎么会丢给空降部队?
How is it that the 4th Army's problem gets dumped on the airborne?
皮卡克中尉! 康普顿中尉! 温特斯上尉!
Lt. Peacock, Lt. Compton, Capt. Winters.
- 戴克中尉 我一直在找你 - 长官 麻烦了
- Lt. Dike, I've been looking for you. - We have a problem.
史崔尔中校去伦敦参加婚礼还没回来 你相信吗?
Col. Strayer is not back from some wedding in London. Can you believe that?
我们都要上前线了 而指挥官甚至都不在同一个国家
We're going to the front here and our CO isn't even in the same country.
戴克中尉 有个很严重的问题
You have a bigger problem. Lt. Dike
你们的弟兄将会缺乏足够的冬装和弹药回到战场
Men are returning to action without proper cold weather clothing or enough ammo.
长官?
Sir?
我建议你到整个基地尽量找
I suggest you take a canvass of the entire base.
尽可能在出发前将物资凑齐
Get what materials you have before you roll out.
- 或许你已经在做了? - 还没 长官
- Or have you done that already? - No, sir.
尽量做到Ｋ级补给
K-rations, as many as you can scrounge.
- 我们不知何时才会再补给 - 是的 长官!
- We don't know if we'll be resupplied. - Yes, sir.
- 弹药怎么办? - 没有多余的弹药了
- What about ammo? - There is no more ammo.
尽可能在弟兄间平均分配 让每人至少都有一点
Distribute it as best you can so at least everybody has something.
是的 长官!
Yes, sir.
康普顿中尉 皮卡克中尉 告知宣姆士中尉这情况
Lt. Compton, Lt. Peacock, inform Lt. Shames of the situation.
将你们的排尽可能的补齐装备
Equip your platoons as best you can...
然后回来向我报告 懂吗?
...and then report to me, understood?
- 是 长官! - 上尉!
- Yes, sir. - Captain.
我猜并没有实施灯火管制 德国空军一定在睡觉
I guess the blackout's not in effect. Luftwaffe must be asleep.
这一天内的变化真大 对不对 中尉?
What a difference a day makes, Lieutenant.
老天 我真想念那些C47
Christ, I miss those C-47s.
我们要从这群卡车里跳伞
We've got a tailgate jump here.
我只想知道要送我们去哪 还有没弹药怎么办?
Where are they sending us? What are we supposed to do with no ammo?
小子! 再说一次你的名字
Kid, what's your name again?
索斯 索斯二世
Suerth. Suerth, Junior.
- 你有弹药吗 索斯? - 只有身上带的
- You got any ammo, Junior? - Just what I'm carrying.
那袜子呢? 你有多的袜子吗?
What about socks, Junior? You got extra socks?
- 一双! - 你最少需要四双
- A pair. - You need four, minimum.
双脚 双手 脖子 蛋蛋 多出来的袜子让他们都保暖
Feet, hands, neck, balls. Extra socks warms them all.
好 都记得这一点 但我们有多带袜子吗?
Okay, we all remember that one. But did we remember the socks?
没错 我愿意用我的靴子来换一包烟
I'd give my goddamn boots for a cigarette.
- 我们没弹药也没袜子 - 有人有烟吗?
- We're out of ammo and socks. - Anybody got a cigarette?
- 我打赌二世一定两样都有很多 - 我没有
- I bet Junior's got plenty of both. - I don't.
- 那帽子呢? 你有帽子吗? - 你有多余的弹药吗?
- How about a hat, you got a hat? - You got extra ammo?
- 那外套呢? 你有外套吗? - 我要小便
- What about a coat, you got a coat? - I need to pee.
那烟呢?
How about some smokes then?
- 有 我有些烟 - 你总算说人话了
- Yeah, I got some smokes. - Now you're talking.
- 丢上来 传过来 - 谁借我个火
- Over here. Pass them down. - Somebody, give me a light.
继续前进 向前走
Keep moving. Come on, keep it coming.
转到左边来
Over to the left.
继续开过来 一直走过去
Keep it moving. All the way down.
下车 伙计们
Get moving, guys.
好了 你们有15分钟 拿到烟的赶快抽
All right guys, 15 minutes. Smoke 'em if you got 'em.
- 大家注意保暖 - 我们到底在哪里?
- Keep warm, guys. - Where the hell are we?
肯定不是在地狱 这里太冷了
Sure we ain't in hell, it's too damn cold.
你们退后点 我已经憋了一小时
Stand back, guys. I've been holding this for the last hour.
有火柴吗?
Anybody got any matches?
这样好多了 靠过来 大家围过来
Gather round, guys.
就停在这儿 别去任何地方 欢迎来到比利时
Wait right here, don't go anywhere. Welcome to Belgium.
这里叫巴斯通
This area's known as Bastogne.
是战略要道
Strategic crossroads town.
七条道路进 七条道路出
Seven roads leading in, seven roads leading out...
很适合德军装甲部队行动
...which makes it ideal for Kraut armor.
艾克要让...
Now, lke wants to make sure...
德军无法使用这些道路
...that the Krauts can't use those roads...
所以我们将在巴斯通周围设阵地、挖战壕
...so, we'll put a perimeter around Bastogne...
象虱子一样深深粘着
...dig in tight as a tick.
- 第二营将部署在东边的森林区 - 感谢老天!
- 2nd Battalion will deploy to the east in this wooded area. - Thank God...
- 差点没赶上 - 去找你的值星官 鲍伯
- ...barely made it. - Better get yourself some ODS, Bob.
好的
Okay.
第一营在北作为你的左翼
1st Battalion's to the north on your left flank.
第三营为预备队
3rd Battalion's in reserve. Andy, let's roll.
- 长官 我们缺少弹药 - 差多少?
- Sir, we're a little short on ammunition. - How short?
营区都限额补给 长官
There was a limited supply in camp, sir.
上尉 我不管你去求 去借 或偷 都得守好这
Captain, you beg, borrow, or steal ammo, but you defend this area.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
我的老天
Jesus Christ.
比尔 唐 过来 看看这个...
Bill, Don, come here, look at this.
拜托 老天 我尿完了
Hold on. Jesus, I'm done.
搞什么
What the...
到底发生了什么事?
What the hell is going on?
你们走错方向了
You're going the wrong way.
朋友
Pal.
发生什么了? 你们要去哪里?
Pal, what happened? Where the hell are you going?
他们突然冒出来屠杀我们
They came out of nowhere, they slaughtered us.
- 你们得离开这 - 我们才刚到 - 把你的弹药给我
- You gotta get outta here. - We just got here. - Give me your ammo.
- 快点! - 拿去! 你会用的上的
- Come on. - Take it, you'll need it.
走吧 离开这里
Go on, get out of here.
我的老天
Jesus Christ
- 过来 谁有弹药? - 你有弹药吗?
- Who's got ammo? - You got ammo?
- 给我你的弹药 - 谁有弹药?
- Gimme your ammo. - Who's got ammo?
- 你有弹药吗? - 快 拿过来
- You got any grenades? - Come on, hand 'em over.
- 拿过来 - 你有手榴弹吗?
- Gimme it. - You got grenades?
- 李 你有手榴弹吗? - 谁有手榴弹?
- Got any grenades, Lieb? - Who's got grenades?
阿兵哥 你有什么?
Private, what have you got?
让一让!
Make a hole!
让一让! 嘿~ 让一让!
Make a hole! Make a hole.
我拿到弹药了 能拿多少就来拿
I got ammo, grab what you can.
中尉 你真是上天恩赐
Lieutenant, you're a godsend.
- 情况怎么样? - 我听说你们要来
- What's the situation? - I heard you guys were coming in.
那里有个弹药堆积场 所以我就...
There was an ammo dump, so here.
只有你们101空降师吗?
Is it just you guys in the 101st?
看来是这样 你们遭到什么攻击?
Looks like. What hit you fellows?
什么都有
Everything.
德军有虎式坦克、豹式坦克、自走炮、斯图卡俯冲轰炸机
The Krauts had tigers, panthers, SPs, stukers...
还有不断涌进的步兵
And infantry that just kept on coming.
- 你叫什么名字 中尉? - 乔治莱斯 第10装甲师
- What's your name, Lieutenant? - George Rice, 10th Armor.
- 好样的! - 你们还有迫击炮弹吗 长官?
- Good work, son. - You got any more mortar rounds, sir?
我们不够了
We're real short.
可以的话 我会再去拿一些 可别期望太高
I'll try to make another ammo run if I can, but don't count on anything.
谢谢你! 这个我拿走 上尉
Thank you, sir. I'll take this, Captain.
一个德军装甲师要切断向南的道路
A panzer division's about to cut the road south.
你们可能会被包围
Looks like you guys are gonna be surrounded.
我们是伞兵 中尉! 本来就该被包围的
We're paratroopers, Lieutenant. We're supposed to be surrounded.
- 祝好运! - 谢谢!
- Good luck. - Thanks.
Ｅ连在没有炮兵及空中支援下
进入巴斯通附近的森林区
粮食和弹药不足 更没有御寒大衣
在你心里最深处有撤退的念头 事实上 它根本不存在
所以小心翼翼地挖你的掩体 并全神贯注地等待
葛拉锡训练营506空降伞兵团剪贴簿